you communicate with Ukrainians in Charletka
вы общаетесь с украинцами в Чар летке
to calm down your internal
чтобы успокоить свои внутренние
psychological problems and anxieties
психологические проблемы и тревожности
so
так
Hello Hello, I’m from the city of
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте я из города
Khmelnitsky
Хмельницкий Вы
Where are you from now? I’m from the city of Gyumri, Armenia I
откуда сейчас я из города Гюмри Армения
know You’re some kind of military Russian
знаю Вы военный какой-то российский
netsy I understand because there was a military base there
нетси понял потому что там военная база
Yes there is one and  now I
же стояла Да есть такая и сечас есть
understand and the World Cup are communicating
понял а ЧМ общаетесь
topics for example
темы например
Well, of course now, for the most part, it’s
Ну конечно сейчас по большей части
Russian aggression So what do you want to say about
России Так и что вы хотите сказать об
this, it’s like I was in an interview, I’m like such a
этом я как будто на интервью попал я как
significant person Yes, what do I
будто такая значимая личность Да что я
want to say? I condemn the bench press, that’s why
хочу сказать я мы осуждаю жима поэтому
we’re here So  that you will do honor in
мы здесь Так а что вы сделаете честь в
roulette
рулетке
in chat
в чат
roulette we run
рулетке мы ведём
anti-war we don’t do it’s just
антивоенного не делаем просто
boring you run anti-war campaigns And
скучно вы ведёте антивоенные компании И
choose Ukraine for
выбираете Украину для
conversation Well, now you asked
разговора Ну вот сейчас Вы когда задали
this question to me and it became funny like what are
этот вопрос мне и стало смешно типа что
you doing in the chat I felt so funny well that’s
вы делаете в чат Мне так смешно стало ну
why I  I decided to answer with irony,
Поэтому я решил с иронией ответить ведём
let's now without Irony What are you doing
Давайте теперь без Иронии Что вы делаете
in the cha
в ча
is difficult to perceive without Irony
это сложно без Иронии
Well,
воспринимать Ну
like Well, look, I answer without Irony I
типа Ну смотри я без Иронии отвечаю я
run an anti-war company on chatroulette,
веду в чатрулетке антивоенное компанию
so I communicate with Russians What about you, the
поэтому общаюсь с россиянами А вы что
children in Letki don’t do anything,
дети в Летки ничего не делаю чаёк
drink tea with people  and Ukraine Why are
попивают с людьми а Украину Зачем
you choosing? I want to talk to the Ukrainians What is the
выбираете хочу поговорить с украинцами О
current situation about?
текущей ситуации Для
Why,
чего
fathers,
батюшки наверное наверное мне
it probably somehow psychologically helps me to
это как-то психологически помогает
survive this situation, I understand everything, that
переживать эту ситуацию всё понял то
is, you communicate with Ukrainians in a chat
есть вы общаетесь с украинцами в чат
room to calm your internal
летке чтобы успокоить свои внутренние
psychological problems and anxieties,
психологические проблемы и тревожности
so it’s probably
так наверное
cool  those are Cool It's Well, it's cool
прикольно те Прикольно Это Ну прикольно
that like your country attacked our
что типа ваша страна напала на нашу
country And you instead you are a citizen of this
страну А вы вместо вы гражданин этой
country you instead that instead of
страны вы вместо того что вместо того
overthrowing Putin I'm sitting here for
чтобы свергать Путина здесь по
fun look you don't know but it's funny not for
прикольчик сижу смотри вы не знаю по
fun it's good that
прикольчик не по прикольчик хорошо что
you haven't joined the army already  no No, let me
вы не пошли в арми уже нет Нет давайте я
speak for myself, what I want to say is you,
скажу за себя что я хочу сказать вы
instead of taking any
вместо того чтобы делать какие-то
actions to influence
действия чтобы повлиять на то чтобы
stopping this war, that is, choose
остановить эту войну то есть выбирать
Russia and communicate with Russia, wait, I’ll
Россию и общаться с росси подождите я
listen to the end, choose Ro and communicate with
дослушайте выбирать ро и общаться с
your citizens so that there are fewer people
вашими гражданами так чтобы меньше людей
in Russia supported the war, you choose
в России поддерживало войну вы выбираете
Ukraine so that with the help of the Ukrainians you will
Украину чтобы с помощью украинцев вам
feel psychologically calmer, otherwise it’s difficult for you to worry. That is, you are the Ukrainians
сложно переживать То есть вы украинцам
who have missiles flying into their cities. Yes, with
которым в города прилетают ракеты Да с
their help you want to calm yourself down. This is
помощью их хотите себя успокоить Это
some kind of
какой-то
nonsense, probably if you turn it around like that, then yes Well yes
бред наверно если это так повернуть то
Yes, what are you
да да А вы что
saying? I’m telling you, I’m
Я же говорю я веду
anti-war and I communicate with Russians
антивоенная и общаюсь с россиянами
who work out for the war, and
которые за войну получается получается
how many have gone over to your side, a
да сколько перешли на вашу сторону очень
lot of them, look, there are people who
много смотрите есть люди которые
meet me and say, look, Andrey,
встречают меня и говорят смотрите Андрей
I watched your videos, I changed my
я смотрел ваши эти видео я изменил своё
mind. I used to think there  about Donbass
мнение Я раньше думал там про Донбасс
this way and that. Now I understand. There are people
так и так Теперь я понял Есть люди
who write to me in a personal message Andrey, I
которые пишут мне в личку Андрей я
changed my mind. When I saw you, at first I
изменил своё мнение Я видя вас я сначала
didn’t understand what was happening, yes, that is, there
не понимал что что происходит да то есть
is always some percentage
есть всегда есть какой-то процент на
that we can influence if out of 10,000
который мы можем повлиять если из 10.000
people or  there out of a thousand people we can
людей или там из тысячи людей мы сможем
reach ten and one of them
Достучаться к десятку а один из них
would like to go to war and because of this he didn’t
хотел бы пойти на войну и из-за этого не
go, this is already huge. Huge If
пошёл это уже огромная Огромно Если
every person can
каждый человек сможет за полтора года
dissuade one from going to
отговорить одного от того чтобы пойти на
war against Ukraine in a year and a half, then a thousand of them
войну против Украины да то тысячу таких
a person to dissuade a thousand people and what
человек отговорить тысячу людей а что
is a thousand people? These are a thousand people
такое тысячу людей это тысячу людей
who didn’t get to the front Russia
которые не попали на фронт Россия
who didn’t kill people, which means they won’t
которые не убивали людей они значит не
kill 300 people from Ukraine because in
убьют 300 людей из Украины потому что
order to kill these thousand, let
чтобы их убить этих тысячу Да погибнет
200-300
там 200-300
Ukrainians die there, that’s what they need to
украинцев вот что надо
do, they are their own  psychological problems
делать они свои психологические проблемы
are solved at the expense of the Ukrainians, in order to
решают за счёт украинцев чтобы с ними
talk to them with the Russians, you need to tell them
поговорить с русскими надо говорить
to choose Russia, because I tell everyone who is against
выбирать России потому я всем кто против
the war in Russia, you should choose
войны в России говорю Вы должны выбирать
not Ukraine, you should choose Russia and
не Украину Вы должны выбирать Росси и
explain to your fellow citizens, talk to
своим согражданам объяснять говорить с
them what this war gives you, prices
ними что вам даёт эта война цены
have increased, sanctions And  so on, so as
повысились санкции И так дальше так
to form people’s non-perception of
чтобы формировать у людей невосприятие
this war, that’s all, the recipe is very
этой войны вот и всё рецепт очень
simple. Yes, you’re probably
простой Да наверное Вы
right, what kind of
правы
fight
что сейчас за борьба
is going on now? I said everything I wanted, I said it. Well,
идёт Я высказал всё что я хотел я же
no, yes, I’m sitting and just
высказал Ну нет я да я сижу и просто
thinking, well, looking at you, Yes, but this
думаю ну Глядя на вас Да но это
not some kind of visual skirmish Yes,
не какая-то зрительная перепалка Да
you are probably
наверное Вы
right, a lot of resources are needed for this, I
правы очень много ресурса нужно на это я
think what you say should be done now
думаю как вы говорите делать сейчас
in order for me to do this, but yes, this is
чтобы э мне этим заниматься но но да это
much more important than what I do. Well, what are the
намного важнее чем то чем я занимаюсь Ну
resources? Look if you find
как ресурсы Смотрите если вы находите
the time to go into the chat  Letka and play with
время выйти в чату летку и поиграть с
Ukraine, it means you have a temporary resource,
Украиной значит у вас ресурс временной
it’s not No, look, it’s
есть это же нет Нет смотрите это
temporary Yes, I mean some kind of
же временной Да я имею в виду какую-то
psychic force, something
силу психическую что-то
like that,
такое
and what is that
а что что ту такого
psychic force? You, as a human being, don’t need to
психического вы как человек ные вещи
convince people of things, so look, people don’t need to  You
убеждать так смотри чело не надо
can convince by just looking. You just don’t
убеждать можно просто смотреть Просто не
have to tell the person everything. Stand up
надо говорить человеку всё Вставай
against the war. It’s just that you are a Russian
против войны Просто вы вот вы россиянин
and he is a Russian. You don’t say that you
и он россиянин вы не говорите что вы
left somewhere there. And so on, just
где-то там выехали И так дальше просто
say, I’m there, for example, from such and such a
говорите я там например из такого-то
city and But here we are, damn it  prices
города и А вот у нас блин цены
have increased And you, as simple as life,
повысились А у вас как просто жизни
says there’s no need to quarrel, it’s very
говорит не надо ссориться это очень
simple psychologically Well, it turns out to be a lie Yeah I understand Yes I
просто психологически Ну это врать
understand, that is, if your
понял Да понял то есть если ваши
moral feelings are like that, I can’t
моральные эти чувства такие не могу
say Why are you not in Russia now,
сказать Да что вы там сейчас не в России
but okay, I’m in Armenia now
да хорошо скажете Я сейчас в Армении
left Yes, and talk to them about life,
выехал Да и поговори с ними о жизни в
what’s the problem? It’s so hard not to
чём проблема Это что так тяжело не
convince But it’s just hard to
убеждать А просто по тяжело
talk
разговаривать
SJ those
СЖ те
who
кто
hesitate such kitchens are very few oche ku cha most
колеблется таких кух очень мало оче ку
very very little pain
ча большин очень очень мало боль
most of them than youth for example
большинство таких чём молодёжь например
Meet the youth Yes and ask
Встречайте молодёжь Да и спрашивайте
also Well  and what’s the problem? I don’t
также Ну а в чём проб настолько я не
sit here so often that I
настолько здесь часто сижу чтобы а со
don’t know how many people you’ve already talked to today, maybe ten. Well,
сегодня не знаю может с десятью Ну вот
if you talked to ten, like from
если вы с десятью поговорили типа из
Russia, one would have something left
России уже бы у одного что-то отложилось
somewhere,
гдето
probably I don’t know, maybe I  I
наверное не знаю может быть я
probably talked to about three people
разговаривал наверное человека три
in Russia who were just
попалось в России которые были прямо
such confident
такие уверенные
people
люди
and what are you
и о чём вы
talking about, you need strength to talk to them,
говорите нужна сила чтобы с ними
that well, you need strength to
разговаривать что ну нужна сила чтобы с
talk to them, that is, you are like a
ними разговаривать нужна То есть вам как
wife Yes,
жне
you really
Да вы прямо меня
humiliate me, look, you say that you need
унижает смотри вы говорите что нужна
strength.  Yes, you say that you
сила То есть вы говорите что у вас как
don’t seem to have the strength to talk to
бы нет силы говорить с
people, a thirty-eight-year-old man, you
людьми тридцати восьмилетний мужчина
agree how I humiliate you, you
тите согласитесь как я унижаю вас вы
humiliate yourself, you say that you don’t have the strength right You
себя унижает вы го что вас нет сил пря
look, you even took such a pose
Вы прям смотрите даже позу такую заняли
from me Yes, a little with contempt. The pose
у меня Да вот немножко с презрением Поза
is not humiliating, contempt.  there is some kind of yes
не унижаю презрение есть какое-то да
When a 38-year-old man says that
Когда мужчина 38 лет говорит что е у
he doesn’t have enough strength to talk to
нему не хватает силы говорить с
people like that
людьми так
and I look Yes, I’m with contempt, you
и я смотрю Да я с презрением у меня на
can see some kind of
лице прямо читается какое-то знаешь
contempt on my face, you know, because I’m sure that it
презрение потому что я уверен что это ни
won’t affect anything  that I’ll tell some
на что не повлияет что я какого-то если
guy
чувака
from Krasnodar that prices
- из Краснодара скажу ему что цены
have increased Like you just told me
повысились Как вы мне только что сказали
that this won’t affect anything Uh-huh, let’s say
что это ни на что не повлияет
from the conversations
Угу Угу давайте так вы из из разговоров
out of a thousand people, one will have something
из тысячи людей у одного что-то
stuck in his
отложится в
head for a
голове
second
секунду
Yes yes  I
Да да я
’m back nya legs Well, I’m saying, well, at the
вернулся ня ноги Ну и говорю чтож уже в
age of 38 he says that he doesn’t have the strength
38 лет говорит что у него нет силы
to talk to others Yes, that’s what it is If you
говорить с другими Да это такое Если Вы
talked to a thousand people Yes, in a year, do you
поговорили с тысячу людьми Да за год у
think something would have been
кого-то одного как думаете что-то бы
left behind for one of them, of course I didn’t talk for
отложилось конечно не поговорил за за
a year with a thousand people, I say. Now,
год с тысячу людми я говорю Вот если
if you talk to a thousand people in
если поговорить за с тысячу людьми за
a year, something would be left in them,
год да отложилось бы у них
damn it, don’t
что-то блин не
hang up. He switched the campaign,
Зависай Походу он переключил ти
that is, the dude is a citizen of the Russian
то есть чувак гражданин Российской
Federation Yes, he went to Armenia Yes, so that they
Федерации Да выехал в Армению Да чтобы
don’t call him on mobile phones, that’s already at least  good
его не мобили звали это уже хоть хорошо
Yes, but he sits and chooses Ukraine. I always
Да но он сидит выбирает Украину Я всегда
ask them why, so that it
их спрашиваю для чего для того чтобы ему
’s somehow easier for him to
психологически как-то было легче
survive psychologically. Yes, he chooses his ilk.
пережить есть о выбирает жну
Yes, who are sitting under shelling and under
Да которые сидят под обстрелами да под
bombers; they are worried. Yes, and he wants them
бомбардиров них тревоги Да и он хочет
to [ __ ] feel sorry for [ __ ], come on, dude
чтобы бля пожалели бля давай тебя чувак
you poor thing How are you there in Armenia in
бедненький ты Как ты там в Армении в
Gyumri you are worried you are not cold there Is there
Гюмри переживаешь тебе там не холодно А
anything to eat And what is there you don’t have
есть Что покушать А что там у тебя нету
anxiety God how you
трево Боже ты Как ты сегодня
slept today [ __ ] up I just don’t like these people like you
спал [__] вот просто не люблю вот этих
know how I don’t know how some kind of rag it’s
таких знаете как не знаю как тряпка
just this  tin How can you be
какая-то просто это жесть Как можно быть
like this, subscribe to th Telegram right now,
таким подпишись на й Telegram прям зараз
VN axis and
ось ВН а
so on, more and more
пок це дуже и дуже
respectfully
важливо